<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Lionel Pinheiro Boots 2022</title>
        <description>My journey throught the rxb&#39;s boots</description>
        <link href="https://lionelpinheiro.com/bootsfeed.xml" rel="self"/>
        <link href="https://lionelpinheiro.com/boots/"/>
        <id>https://lionelpinheiro.com/boots/</id>
            <item>
                <title>Week 1 - VM Ubuntu Server Markdown Zettelkasten</title>
                <guid>
            https://lionelpinheiro.com/boots/week1/
            </guid>
                <link href="
            https://lionelpinheiro.com/boots/week1/
            "/>
                <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 12:19:35 GMT</pubDate>
                <description type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Week 1 - VM Ubuntu Server Markdown Zettelkasten&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Zettelkasten&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zettlekasten is a method created by Niklas Luhmann a very prolific German sociologist and philosopher, the method consist in building a box of notes. Each note has to be about one subject only if I have to explain something else related to the topic I should create another card, and link them with tags. Every note/card contains a unique identifier, a title, the content, and tags. The content length should have 25 maximum writing lines but can also have images or code snippets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advantage of this method? Using my own words to better assimilate knowledge and easier to revue the idea is appealing but I feel it requires a lot of discipline to do it regularly and maintain it. Using English can also be time-consuming and draining maybe I should do it in french it&#39;s something I should think about.
I will still give it a shot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was recommended to host it on github because it offers some functionalities a build-in editor, displays markdown, and a search functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;VM - Ubuntu Server&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the main tasks during this week was creating a lab where we could practice safely whithout the fear of breaking a system. For doing so at my understanding we could have choose between containers with docker but as beginners I think the learning curve could be to harsh, dualbooting but some mistakes can happen for example deleting a operating system already present on the machine (personnal experience).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we use a virtual machine with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.virtualbox.org/&quot;&gt;virtualbox&lt;/a&gt;, thing that I have never done before, and I can see why it was recommended easy to install, I can create delete VM at ease.
As OS we install Ubuntu Server as seems to be one of the most use OS in production. RedHat and Amazon linux were mentioned but as proprietary system they are more difficult to optain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I already have some experience with servers basic stuff like connecting to it with SHH connection installing apache server but managing key and connection to different servers was a little painfull so I try to go little further and look how I could manage that.
I found a couple of videos on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/linode/search?query=ssh&quot;&gt;linode&lt;/a&gt; youtube channel on this topic where I learn about :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a Config file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a ed25519 SHH key&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Link a key to a server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SSH agent ?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mardown&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also aboard the subject of markdown a markup language that can be converted into HTML. I was already familiar with it because I&#39;m using eleventy a framework to build this website that uses markdown format files to create pages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <author>
                    <name>Lionel Pinheiro</name>
                    <email>contact.pinheiro.lionel@gmail.com</email>
                </author>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Week 2 - Command Line, Teletype, Linux file system, package management</title>
                <guid>
            https://lionelpinheiro.com/boots/week2/
            </guid>
                <link href="
            https://lionelpinheiro.com/boots/week2/
            "/>
                <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 12:27:18 GMT</pubDate>
                <description type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Week 2 - Command Line, Teletype, Linux file system, package management&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Command Line&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&#39;s the difference between a CLI a terminal and the shell ?
A terminal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;is a program that opens a window and lets you interact with the shell &lt;em&gt;by Willian Shotts from The Linux command line book&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CLI = Command Line Interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;shell  = interractive programm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Linux file system&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Package management&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A package are a collections of compressed files once installed the package will become a program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do I know I&#39;m not downloading a dangerous package ? Every packages in Ubuntu main are audited by the ubuntu security team and thos packages are also maintained and support by the Ubuntu project.
You can found information about all the packages available in Ubuntu &lt;a href=&quot;https://packages.ubuntu.com/en/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have been through the process of managing the installation, deletion, and updating of a package.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <author>
                    <name>Lionel Pinheiro</name>
                    <email>contact.pinheiro.lionel@gmail.com</email>
                </author>
            </item></channel>
</rss>